{
    "id": "bd918144ad5841fe8cea11e179f729d5",
    "title": "Special Uses Of Adjectives",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "…………………….. are not always cowards.",
            "description": "When an adjective is used to denote a class of people, it is always used with the. The cautious means the same as cautious people. ",
            "answers": [
                "Cautious",
                "The cautious",
                "Cautious people"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "23b183906ade4cab8eb71d30d5612230"
        },
        {
            "question": "The richest ……………………….. not always the happiest.",
            "description": "Adjectives used to denote a class of persons are always plural and take the plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b0421af4046f43d482bfe1557e4e4b7d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Blessed as ……………………….",
            "description": "When an adjective is used to denote a class of people, it is always used with the.",
            "answers": [
                "meek",
                "the meek",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6d38482f89404755ad2d699bc2d785a9"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. is uncertain.",
            "description": "Sometimes adjectives are used to denote some abstract quality. In this case also they are used with the article the.",
            "answers": [
                "Future",
                "The future",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5713c2ffb5264a75857a25b39b6e3f2b"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. we know nothing.",
            "description": "No article is used in this expression.",
            "answers": [
                "In short",
                "In the short"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "85d3fb2cb1b74b0189e6a791dffd5d2d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I must have the terms down in ……………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "the black and white",
                "black and white"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "95618c1fa0764a0485bf9d9719e7a9dd"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am afraid his situation is going from ………………………..",
            "description": "No articles are used in these expressions",
            "answers": [
                "bad to worse",
                "the bad to worse"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9538cc2a3acf4b4da62bd831c21f1e70"
        },
        {
            "question": "The unemployed ……………………….. losing hope.",
            "description": "When the + adjective refers to a well-known group of people, it is plural.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0550ff466fcd4f51b91b8ba1c789d8c3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The government should do something to solve …………………………",
            "description": "These expressions cannot be used with the possessive ’s.",
            "answers": [
                "the poor's problems",
                "poor people's problems",
                "the problems of the poor"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0b65530f6fd14cfa87cf9f9374b8d9c3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am ………………………… in my family.",
            "description": "Superlatives are often used without a noun if the meaning is clear.",
            "answers": [
                "the shortest",
                "the shortest person",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "421bf7d568b8427bbc1f4d223143882c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t afford ………………………….",
            "description": "The correct structure is that + adjective /adverb + article + noun",
            "answers": [
                "that a big car",
                "that big a car",
                "that big car"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7772ec4126a44929938d2b382423cb3c"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… is she?",
            "description": "The correct structure is how + adjective / adverb + a/an + noun. Note that the article goes after the noun in this special structure.",
            "answers": [
                "How good a dancer",
                "How good dancer",
                "How a good dancer"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8d271a6e1d784c7abfb600a4ab9d5588"
        }
    ]
}